Guide to the David Richmond Gergen Papers, 1964-1999 (bulk 1971-1992) RL.00443
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2000-0356)
  - Perspectives on Public Policy Conference for senior federal executives,1984, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Current News, 1984 February 3- 1984 February 7 (Box 18)
  - Transcripts from miscellaneous news programs, 1984 February (Box 18)
  - Phone logs,1992 January-1992 November, 5 folders (Box 18)
  - Phone logs, back-ups,1992 July-1992 December, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Videos (Box 18)
    - TV transcripts, WJLA-TV, Banking in Vermont - Socially Responsible (Box 18)
    - Poynter Fellowship at Yale University,1995 March 23 (Box 18)
    - The Oakland Group,The First Act of Democracy (Box 18)
    - Big Daddy Productions, Show #214, "Clinton" (Box 18)
    - David Gergen, Aspen Institute TV show,1994 August 24 (Box 18)
    - Think Tank program 141: The Republican Congress: Is it a New, New Deal? (Box 18)
    - ABC Nightline,1994 September 23 (Box 18)
    - Name Your Adventure, A Day with DeeDee Meyers (Box 18)
  - H. Ross Perot Speech (Box 18)
  - American Bankers Association,1991 April 11-17 (Box 18)
  - Speech notes,1970, 1990-1991 (Box 18)
    - BellSouth (Box 18)
    - Brookings/American Polish Association, 19 November 1991 (Box 18)
    - Common Cause, 14 September 1990 (Box 18)
    - Cotton Council, 10 February 1992 (Box 18)
    - Forging Industry, 11 September 1990 (Box 18)
    - Georgetown Leadership Seminar, 25 October 1990 (Box 18)
    - Global Change Forum, 21 September 1990 (Box 18)
    - Grad school. NYC, 31 July 1991 (Box 18)
  - Office Files (Box 19)
    - Financial: invoices, statements, and receipts
      - Expenses, Traffic tickets and Life and Accident Insurance (Box 19)
      - Expenses,1989-1993, 42 folders (Box 19)
      - Credit Card Statements,1990-1993, 4 folders (Box 19)
      - Income,1989-1993, 29 folders (Box 19)
    - Legal correspondence re: Contracts with ABC and Cosby Bureau International, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Military Project,1988-1989 (Box 19)
    - Biographical information, visas and passport photos,1986-1989 (includes photographs), 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Adweek-USN Story,1988 (Box 19)
  - Office Files (Box 20)
    - Auto insurance and other information, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence,1988, 14 folders (Box 20)
    - Chron File,1988 July-1988 August, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Thank you letters received,1988-1989 (Box 20)
    - Inter-Office Memos,1988, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Convention matchbox and ERA pin (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, including Newsweek,1981,Nixon speech, 1970, and press announcement of Gergen's presentation at the NAGC Conference,type="inclusive"1981 (Box 20)
  - Press passes and one photo of Gergen with Kermit the Frog,1994 (Box 20)
  - [Reagan materials-as labeled by collector] (Box 20)
    - Contact sheets and photos of Ronald and NancyReagan and others,1990 September 18 (Box 20)
    - Notes (in 3 notebooks and one folder),1991 February-1991 March
      - Contact sheets and photos of Ronald and NancyReagan and others,1990 September 18 (Box 20)
      - Notes,1991 February-1991 March, in 3 notebooks and one folder (Box 20)
      - Printed material on US economic growth, 2 volumes (Box 20)
      - Contents of drawer handwritten list,1991 (Box 20)
      - Notes for speeches,1990-1992
        - Japan (Box 20)
        - MBA Enterprise Corps. (Box 20)
        - Meridian House International, 1991 May 14 (Box 20)
        - Miscellaneous-letter size (Box 20)
        - SUNY-Senesco-Wadsworth, 1991 October 29 (Box 20)
        - Wisconsin Power and Light Co., 1990 September 17 (Box 20)
        - Volvo, 1992 January 30 (Box 20)
        - Yale Alumni, 1991 October 17 (Box 20)
        - Nonprescription drug, 1990 May (Box 20)
        - Vital Speeches (Box 20)
        - Boomtime for Lawyers (Box 20)
        - November Races, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Office Files (Box 21)
    - [Reagan materials continued]
      - Notes, continued (Box 21)
      - Miscellaneous-legal size, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Aspen Institute
      - Binder of discussion papers and articles (Box 21)
      - Notes (Box 21)
      - The Aspen Institute Quarterly, Winter1993 (Box 21)
      - Rochester Speech,1992 May (Box 21)
      - Global Impacts of Chinese Economic Growth, by L. Lau,1995 (Box 21)
  - Video tapes, including network appearances,1983-1999 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous audio cassettes (Box 22)
  - Briefing memos to the President,1970s, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - White House Telephone Directory,1975 (Box 23)
  - California briefing book (Box 23)
  - Republican Governors Association,1975, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - RGA Communications,1976 (Box 23)
  - Memos,1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Grenada--Speech, Polls, Clips, etc. (Box 23)
  - Lebanon (Box 23)
  - The President and Congress--Selected Articles (Box 23)
  - Television Syndication (Box 24)
  - 1984 Presidential Election -- Women I (Box 24)
  - Women II (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous files, 16 folders (Box 24)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes professional correspondence, speeches, polling information, phone logs, and personal financial information.
  - Clippings, 6 folders (Box 25)
  - Loan application (Box 25)
  - Financial information,1981 (Box 25)
    Includes expenses and income records, deposits, bills, travel reimbursement and requests, investment and insurance information, and gifts received while working in the White House.
  - The Washington Campus,1984, folder and binder (Box 25)
  - The Washington Campus,1984, folder and binder (Box 25)
  - Addresses,1981, binder (Box 25)
  - DRG Personal White House Files #1 (Box 26)
    - First 100 Days, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Memos re: Press Conferences, binder (Box 26)
    - Correspondence,1981, binder (Box 26)
      Includes congratulatory letters and thank you's
    - New World Information Order,1982 (Box 26)
    - Arms Control,1981-1982 (Box 26)
    - [The President's] Image,1982 (Box 26)
    - Report on Weekly Surrogate and Communication Activities,1981 (Box 26)
    - Printed material (Box 26)
    - NPR's Morning Edition, 1982 October 15, audio tape (Box 26)
  - DRG Personal White House Files #3 (Box 26)
    - Long-Range Calendar,1981 June (Box 26)
    - Radio,1982 (Box 26)
    - Williamsburg Summit,1983 (Box 26)
    - Proposed Executive Order on National Security Information,1982 (Box 26)
  - DRG Personal White House Files #3, continued (Box 27)
    - Freedom of Information Act, binder, 3 folders, audio tape (Box 27)
    - Summary of Public Affairs/Media Relations Activities on the Tax Bill,1982 (Box 27)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #5 (Box 27)
    - Debategate1983, 5 folders (Box 27)
    - Copy of printed material, The Caddell Memorandums, 1988 (Box 27)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #7, 24 folders (Box 28)
    Includes Gergen's notes, memos written by him, invites received, and phone logs, 1983 January-1983 October (copies of public records?)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #2 (Box 29)
    - Ronald Reagan, 7 folders (Box 29)
    - Banks (Box 29)
    - Latin America and Middle East (Box 29)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #8 (Box 29)
    - Demographic profile from the1980 Census, binder (Box 29)
    - Notes on economic advisors, defense budget, and budget working group,1981, 4 folders (Box 29)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #8, continued (Box 30)
    - Memos to DG re: economic package, Public Affairs Office, election1982, 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Notes, memos, and drafts re: speeches,1982-1983 (Box 30)
    - Includes defense, arm control, Central America, and the State of the Union, 5 folders (Box 30)
    - Notes and memos re: media, news planning, and the administration's media policy, 8 folder (Box 30)
    - Memos re: Press Office and press conferences,1983, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - TV Guide Media Study, 1983, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #9 (Box 30)
    - Subject Files
      - Information on DG and Brady, Legislative Strategy, and Poland, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #9, continued (Box 31)
    - Subject Files
      - CBS Bill Moyers Story, 4 folders (Box 31)
      - Social Security (Box 31)
    - Commission Reports: Long, Kissinger, Hunger,1983-1984, binder (Box 31)
    - Fairness II: An Executive Briefing Book,1983, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #10 (Box 31)
    - Articles from various bibliographies, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #10, continued (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous articles and bibliographies, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Presidency and the President Miscellaneous Articles and Clips (Box 32)
    - NSDD-Safeguarding National Security (Box 32)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #12 (Box 32)
    - DG Senior Staff Meeting Notes,1981-1983, 4 folders (Box 32)
    - GOP and Bipartisan Leadership Meetings [Notes], 2 folders (Box 32)
    - JAB Staff Meeting Notes (Box 32)
    - DG Meetings with President [Notes],1983 (Box 32)
    - Deaver Planning Meetings (Box 32)
    - Legislative Strategy and Liaison,1983 (Box 32)
    - SPG-Special Planning Group,1983 (Box 32)
    - Reagan Speeches and Handwritten Notes (copies only of Reagan's handwriting) (Box 32)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #12, continued (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous Notes from Alphabetical File,1983, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - The Day After (Box 33)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #13 (Box 33)
    - Fairness Doctrine and National Association of Broadcasters, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - The First 100 Days (Box 33)
    - Economics and Education (Box 33)
    - Hispanics (Box 33)
    - CSIS Congressional Leadership Group (Box 33)
  - DRG Personal White House Files, #13, continued (Box 34)
    - Republican Convention1984 (Box 34)
    - Civil Rights Commission, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Irma Kanter Projects (1983 August) (Box 34)
    - Irma Kanter Media Report: Demographic Information and Rating Statistics (Box 34)
    - Civil Rights Commission Transcript (Rough Draft),1983 July 22 (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous memos re: Mondale/Reagan polls, Re-elect Committee, and Reagan radio address (Box 34)
    - Ronald Reagan Campaign Pledges-1981 (Box 34)
    - Leaks, Leaks (Box 34)
    - Presidential Candidates (Box 34)
    - Quotes (Box 34)
    - Taxes (Box 34)
    - J. Walter Thompson (Dave Clausen Meeting) (Box 34)
    - 1984 State of the Union (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous memos, clips, and speeches re: KAL Incident (Box 34)
  - DRG White House Files, #6 (Box 34)
    - 1982 Chron File, 3 folders (Box 34)
      Including desk notes, phone logs, memos, correspondence, and election notes
  - DRG White House Files, #6, continued (Box 35)
    - 1982 Chron File, continued, 25 folders (Box 35)
  - DRG Personal files-'Transition' Period (Box 36)
    - Photo of Gergen (Box 36)
    - Personal materials, 20 folders (Box 36)
      Includes summer house, bar application, passport information, vita, general correspondence and correspondence toRonald Reagan headquarters, chron file, and financial information
    - Miscellaneous Notes re: transition (Box 36)
    - White House organization (Box 36)
    - American Attitudes Toward Government, by Gergen, as well as other materials regarding The Brookings Institution (Box 36)
  - Pre- Reagan #8 (Box 36)
    - Speeches-Miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - Pre-Reagan #8, continued (Box 37)
    - Speeches, memos, and preparatory materials labeled by subject, 19 folders (Box 37)
      IncludesBush, Transportation, Economics, Oil, Iowa, SALT, and Welfare Policy
    - Kristol (foreign policy) (Box 37)
    - Economic (Box 37)
    - Bush-Issues (Box 37)
  - #9 Schedule Book-Mid-East Trip; Yale Alum Materials (Box 37)
    - Visit ofRichard Nixon to the Middle East,1974, binder and 2 folders-note mildew on binder (Box 37)
    - Yale Alumni Fund, 1964-1972, 3 folders (Box 37)
  - 12 Mostly Speech Drafts,1974 RN Speeches; Also: DG Memos to and FM WH Staff1973 June-1973 September; DG Memos to and FM Writing Staff (Box 37)
    - Background Materials-1974 1. Energy msg 2. Campaign Reform msg, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - #12 Mostly Speech Drafts, continued (Box 38)
    - Annapolis Speech,1974 June (Box 38)
    - Background materials for various speeches,1974, 9 folders (Box 38)
      Includes various radio addresses and other appearances on topics such as the economy, campaign reform, energy, State of the Union
    - Memos to/from WH Staff January-1973 September (Box 38)
    - Memos to and from Writing Staff,1972-1973 (Box 38)
  - DG Memos to WH Staff1976; 2 yr. Reports, 33 folders (Box 39)
    Memos to and from White House Staff labeled by individual name and including a file on the President
  - Various binders (Box 39)
    - Debate Briefing Book-Economic Issues, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Debate Briefing Book-Domestic Issues (Box 39)
    - DRG Calls and Messages,1975 November 24-1976 May 21 and1976 May 21-1976 August 23, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - The Battle of the Budget,1973 (Box 39)
  - Binders, continued (Box 40)
    - Nixon Family/Friends (Box 40)
    - Renewal in the Ghetto, by Gergen,1967, bound volume, 2 copies (Box 40)
    - The President's Debate (Box 40)
    - [Resumes and requests for job assistance],1976 (Box 40)
    - State of the Union1972, Input-WH Staff (Box 40)
    - American Enterprise Institute Program Book (Box 40)
      [ this was printed on binder; binder contains handwritten notes that appear to be from classes on real estate]
    - Ford Issues Book (Box 40)
    - CH VII: The Role of the Courts in the Interpretation of Statues [class material?] (Box 40)
    - HJC Hearings-1974, 3 folders (Box 40)
    - The First 100 Days (Box 40)
    - Appendix 30-49, 20 envelopes (Box 40)
    - American Attitudes Toward Foreign Affairs, by Gergen,1980, binder (Box 40)
    - unspecified (Box 40)
  - [Subject Binders], including Energy, Economics, Foreign Policy, and Defense, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - [Alternate Programming at the1976 Convention], 3 folders (Box 41)
  - [Speeches and preparatory materials by Gergen and William E. Simon] (materials in envelopes and clippings), 25 folders (Box 41)
  - WES 1974 November 6-1975 October 22 (Box 41)
    - [Speech drafts], 1974-1975, 3 folders (Box 41)
    - Center on Foreign and Defense Policy (Gergen) (Box 41)
  - #15, Personal Papers; RP-DG Correspondence (Partial); Partial 1972 Telephone Logs; 1972 Election Nite; Memorable Quotes (Box 41)
    - HJC Hearings-1979 July 29, 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Carter Files, 1976-1977 (Box 41)
    - Campaign letters (1976 December ) (Box 41)
    - [Correspondence], 1977 (Box 41)
    - Jimmy Carter 's Betrayal of the South by Jeffrey St. John (a copy of the book) (Box 41)
  - #15 Personal Papers, continued (Box 42)
    - Memorable Quotes, Mostly RN, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Memos to/from Ray Price (Box 42)
    - [Memorandum] (Box 42)
    - 1972: Planning Calendar for Legislators (Box 42)
    - Telephone Messages (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous notes on legal pad (Box 42)
    - Nixon Family/Friends: Needham (Box 42)
    - Campaign Finances: Needham (Box 42)
    - President's Finances (Box 42)
  - WES1974 November 6- 1975 October 22, continued (Box 42)
    - McGrew Award Ceremony (Box 42)
    - Jackson Subcommittee (Box 42)
    - Swearing-In of Mary Brooks (Mint), 1974 August 8 (Box 42)
    - Senate Finance Comm., 1974 August 6 (Box 42)
    - Talking Pts. on the Econ., 1974 July 31 (Box 42)
    - Sheraton Park Hotel, 1974 October 1 (Box 42)
    - 1974 World Energy Conference, 1974 September 23 (Box 42)
    - Waldorf Astoria Hotel, 19 September 1974 (Box 42)
    - Nat'l Petroleum Council, 1974 September 10 (Box 42)
    - Talking Pts. Administrative Assistants, 1974 August 7 (Box 42)
    - Senate Finance Committee, 1974 August 6 (Box 42)
    - Joint Econ. Committee, 1974 August 2 (Box 42)
    - House Ways and Means, 1974 February 4 (Box 42)
    - Annual Award Ceremony of the Treasury, 1974 October 18 (Box 42)
    - IMF/IBRD Meetings, 1974 October 1 (Box 42)
    - Talking Points Sheraton Park Hotel, 1974 October 1 (Box 42)
    - Senate Budget Committee, 1974 August 15 (Box 42)
    - Sen. Select Comm. On Small Business, 1974 August 13 (Box 42)
    - House Foreign Affairs Comm., 1974 August 12 (Box 42)
  - Carter Files (Box 42)
    - Carter's Georgia Record (Box 42)
    - DĂŠtente (Box 42)
    - 1976 Campaign Overview (Box 42)
    - Vice Pres. Candidates (Box 42)
    - Reorg and Reg Reform (Box 42)
    - Veto Analysis (Box 42)
    - Polls (Box 42)
    - Georgia Records (Box 42)
    - Flip-Flop (Box 42)
    - Demo Platform (Box 42)
    - Debate Strategy (Box 42)
    - Two-Year Report Requests (Box 42)
    - Carter Personality (Box 42)
    - Liberal Attack Pieces (Box 42)
    - Transition File (Box 42)
    - Special File (Box 42)
    - DRG (Staff File) (Box 42)
    - DRG (Special File) (Box 42)
    - (Carter) Presidential File (Box 42)
    - Platform (Box 42)
    - Pol. Philosophy (Box 42)
    - Carter's View of the Presidency (Box 42)
    - Politics and Religion (Box 42)
    - Watergate and Pardon (Box 42)
    - Ford/Carter Comparisons (Box 42)
    - B-1 Bomber (Box 42)
    - Vietnam War (Box 42)
    - Angola (Box 42)
    - Africa (Box 42)
    - International Monetary Policy (Box 42)
    - Why You Should be Elected (Box 42)
    - Carter Campaign (Box 42)
    - Catholics and Jews (Box 42)
    - Administration Stats (Box 42)
    - Chron (Box 42)
  - Carter Files, continued (Box 43)
    - [Press releases],1977 (Box 43)
    - Carter on Domestic and Economic Issues (Box 43)
    - Mayor Pete Wilson-1976 May 19, audio tape (Box 43)
    - [Press Conference briefing] (Box 43)
    - Background information by State,1976, 13 folders (Box 43)
    - Logs for computer disks 2-4, 6, 8-9 (Box 43)
    - Questions and Answers-disk log (Box 43)
    - Disc #6-log (Box 43)
    - Disc #10-log, 3 folders (Box 43)
    - Iowa and Illinois campaign,1976, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - New York and New Jersey Campaign,1976 (Box 43)
  - Handwritten notebooks by Gergen (Box 44)
    - 1990 July-1997 September (select months), 17 folders (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 9 folders (Box 44)
  - Notebooks, continued, 4 folders (Box 45)
  - Hollywood-Burbank Airport (Box 45)
  - Active Memos (Box 45)
  - Convention Film -1976, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Convention, 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Capital Markets, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Fortune - Capital Markets (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Speeches by William Simon, Secretary of Treasury,1975 (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 46)
  - YALE (Box 46)
  - Broadcasting Yearbook,1976 (Box 46)
  - Inaugural Addresses (Box 46)
  - #2 Notebooks and1972 Convention Materials (Box 46)
    - The Battle of the Budget,1973 (Box 46)
    - Energy Message Speech Book,1973 (Box 46)
    - Domestic Policy, Foreign Policy, and Politics [McGovern's positions on] (Box 46)
    - Personnel: Writers-Staff Memos,1973 (Box 46)
  - Carter on Domestic Issues, 1976 [briefing book], 2 folders (Box 46)
  - David R. Gergen-1998 May, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - #2 Notebooks and1972 Convention Materials (Box 47)
    - 1972 Convention, 5 folders (Box 47)
      Includes speeches written for various convention participants
  - Pre-Reagan #6,,Files on Clients (American Pharmaceutical, J.C. Penny, LTV, ABC) ( 1980), 1977-1980 (Box 47)
    - ABC, materials in envelopes (Box 47)
    - LTV, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - The Brethren (Box 47)
    - Citizen's Choice (Box 47)
    - J.C. Penney (Box 47)
  - Pre-Reagan #6, continued (Box 48)
    - Eli Lilly, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Refugee Committee (Box 48)
  - WES Speech File1975 September 23-1975 October 15 (Box 48)
    - AP Managing Editors-Williamsburg 1975 October 15, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Chattanooga Manufacturers 1975 October 14, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Washington World Law Conference 1975 October 14 (Box 48)
    - Presidential Speech #2 (Box 48)
    - Presidential Speech #1 (Box 48)
    - ANPA [American Newspaper Publishers Association] 1975 October 14 (Box 48)
    - Treasury Awards Dinner Date 8 October 1975 (Box 48)
    - Business Council-Hot Springs 1975 October 10 (Box 48)
    - Manufacturers Association Williamsport, PA 1975 October 8 (Box 48)
    - IRS Meeting 1975 October 8 (Box 48)
    - Providence, RI 1975 October 7 (Box 48)
    - Trade and Economic Council Dinner 1975 October 6 (Box 48)
    - President's Tax and Spending Program, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Fla. State Chamber of Commerce-1975 October 2 (Box 48)
    - Secret Service Statement 1975 September 30, 2 folders (Box 48)
  - WES1975 September 23-1975 October 15, continued (Box 49)
    - The Round Table-St. Louis 1975 October 1, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Economic Club of NY-1975 September 23, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - #17 DG Personal Papers; Background Papers re: Key Biscayne, SC; Early Drafts-1974 Messages (Health, Transp., SOTU) (Box 49)
    - Gergen, David R (Personal, Confidential), 2 folders (Box 49)
    - American Experience (Box 49)
    - San Clemente/Key Biscayne (Box 49)
    - Health Insurance Message,1974, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - SOTU1974, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - #17 DG Personal Papers, continued (Box 50)
    - Chron. Files,1972 September-1972 November, 23 folders (Box 50)
  - 17 DG Personal Papers, continued (Box 51)
    - Chron. Files,1972 September (Box 51)
  - Subject Files C-E,1975-1976 (Box 51)
    - Saturday Review (Box 51)
    - Newspaper Articles
      - Riesel Column (Box 51)
      - NY Times (Box 51)
    - Capital Markets, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank (Box 51)
    - Cities (Box 51)
    - Centralized Economy (Box 51)
    - Coal and Miners, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Comics (Box 51)
    - Commerce Department (Box 51)
    - Compassion (Box 51)
    - Conservatism (Box 51)
    - Constitutional Amendments (Box 51)
    - Corporate Accounting (Box 51)
    - Corruption (Box 51)
    - Credit Allocation [PR-memo to senators?] (Box 51)
    - Crime (Box 51)
    - Debt Society (Box 51)
    - Capitalism (Box 51)
    - Democratic Plans (Box 51)
    - Economic Conditions [Dept. of the Treasury memos] (Box 51)
  - Chron. File [mostly memos rather than correspondence],1976 February-1976 September, 21 folders (Box 52)
    Includes memos to Price from Haldeman
  - Subject Files E-G, 1975-1976 (Box 53)
    - Economy, International (Box 53)
    - Economic Planning (Box 53)
    - Elderly (Box 53)
    - Endorsements (Newspapers) (Box 53)
    - Elliott, Bently (confidential) (Box 53)
    - Energy-R & D, 5 folders (Box 53)
    - Evans-Novak Political Report (Box 53)
    - Exxon (Box 53)
    - Federal Reserve (Box 53)
    - Financial Institutions Act (Box 53)
    - Financial Markets (Box 53)
    - Food Stamps and Welfare Programs, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Ford (Mail Opinions) (Box 53)
    - Foreign Countries (Box 53)
    - Foreign Economics (Box 53)
    - Gas, 2 folders (Box 53)
  - DG Subject Files M-P, 1975-1976 (Box 53)
    - McCracken, Paul (Box 53)
    - Minorities (Box 53)
  - DG Subject Files M-P, continued (Box 54)
    - Modern Living (Box 54)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P. (Box 54)
    - Nardi, Michel (Box 54)
    - NAACP (Box 54)
    - US National Survey (Box 54)
    - New England (Box 54)
    - New York, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - New York City Finances, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Off Budget Agencies (Box 54)
    - Oil, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - OPEC, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Pension Funds (Box 54)
    - Ctr for Policy Process (1976 February 28-1976 February 29 weekend) (Box 54)
    - Political Figures (Box 54)
    - Political Parties (Box 54)
    - Post Office (Box 54)
    - President's Economic Program (Box 54)
    - Presidential Correspondence (Box 54)
    - Press and Economics, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Productivity (Box 54)
    - Profits (Box 54)
  - Gergen Subject Files S, 1975-1976 (Box 54)
    - Remarks of William E. Simon before the Foreign Exchange Traders International Congress (Box 54)
    - Simon Speeches, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Sites Information (Box 54)
    - Smith, James (Box 54)